

# Soohwan Kim

#### NLP RESEARCH ENGINEER · SPEECH RESEARCH ENGINEER

16F, Gangnam-daero 382 Merits Tower, Gangnam-District, Seoul, 06232, Korea

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.ai@tunib.ai | 🏕 sooftware.github.io | 🖸 sooftware | 🛅 Soo-hwan

"My dream is to make artificial intelligence like Jarvis in the movie Iron Man."

## About Me

I would like to introduce myself as an AI research engineer rather than a research scientist. My dream is to make artificial intelligence like Jarvis in the movie Iron Man - so I am very interested in deep learning techniques such as speech recognition, speech synthesis, and open-domain dialogue. As for my ability, I can express what I thought neatly in code, and I have the ability to handle various open sources and learn quickly. If you want to check my capabilities, check my github page (https://github.com/sooftware).

## **Education**

#### **Kwangwoon University**

Seoul, South Korea

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, MAJOR IN ELCOMM, MINOR IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.67 / 4.5
- Major/Minor Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

## **Professional Experience**

TUNIB Inc. Gangnam, Seoul

CO-FOUNDER, NLP RESEARCH ENGINEER

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Create conversational digital humans who people emotionally engage with.
- Research and develop the latest NLP technology.
- Webpage: www.tunib.ai [link]

**Kakao Brain** Pangyo, Gyunggi

Speech Research Engineer

Nov. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Research & develop speech and natural language processing fields
- Development PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing [link]

## Internships\_

**Kakao Brain** Pangyo, Gyunggi

Speech Research Intern

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research & Development of automatic speech recognition models
- Development of multilingual speech synthesis model with support for twelve Languages

## **Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)**

Mapo, Seoul

Undergraduate Researcher

· Studies speech recognition techniques based on various machine learning algorithms (e.g. deep learning). [link]

• Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models

Military Service\_\_\_\_\_

ROKMC Served and discharged from Republic of Korea Marine Corps as Signaller, Sergeant, 2015.09 - 2017.06

## **Publication**

- 2021 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, ELSEVIER, SIMPAC
- 2020 End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

March 29, 2021 Soohwan Kim · Résumé

## **Project Experience**

#### PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing

Kakao Brain

MAINTAINER, TEAM MEMBER

Sep. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- PORORO performs Natural Language Processing and Speech-related tasks. [link]
- It is easy to solve various subtasks in the natural language and speech processing field by simply passing the task name.

### **Multilingual Text-To-Speech**

Kakao Brain Oct. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• Development of a model that supports multilingual Text-To-Speech.

· Supports 11 multi-language, Cross-lingual Voice Style Transfer, and Code-Switching functions. [link]

Kakao Brain

THE PERSON IN CHARGE

THE PERSON IN CHARGE

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Listen, Attend and Spell, Transformer, and Wav2vec 2.0 Model experiments
- · Speech recognition speecd and performance comparison by output-units (character, grapheme, etc.)

## KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

English, Chinese, and Korean End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition

Kwanawoon Univ. Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

TEAM LEADER

- · Modular and extensible end-to-end Korean automatic speech recognition (ASR) toolkit
- It is the most popular Korean speech recognition task in gitHub. [link]

## **Extracurricular Activity**

#### **Speech Paper Reading**

Study

GROUP MEMBER

Dec. 2020 - Present

- · Weekly meeting where people who work in the field of Speech gather and read papers.
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

**NLP Paper Reading** Study

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- · Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

**Technical Blog** Blog

WRITER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
- · Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link] [link]

## Skills

Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML **Programming** 

PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Fairseq, Transformers, PyTorchLightning, Wav2letter, Faiss, Hydra **Deep Learning** 

**Data Analysis** Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

## Awards & Honors

## **AWARDS**

2020.11	President's Award	(1st Place)	, Kwangwoon	Engineering Festival
---------	-------------------	-------------	-------------	----------------------

2020.11 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

## **HONORS**

2020.03 School Representative, 5G-based ICT Convergence Service Idea Contest

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University